<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Audio at the Auklab's RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://auklab-audio.github.io</link>
        <description>Updates, publications, and blog posts about Audio at the Auklab.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 14:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 13:57:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
        <generator>  </generator>
        <atom:link href="https://auklab-audio.github.iorss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        
        <item>
            <title>Efficient and Precise Sound Event Annotation</title>
            <link>https://auklab-audio.github.io/blog/efficient-and-precise-sound-event-annotation</link>
            <description>Annotating bioacoustic data is a time-consuming and labor-intensive task. We have therefore developed a method for efficient and precise annotation of local structures in data, which we call adaptive change point detection (A-CPD).</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">/blog/efficient-and-precise-sound-event-annotation</guid>
        </item>
        
        
        
        <item>
            <title>Technological evolution generates new answers and new ways forward: A progress report from the first decade at the Karlsö Auk Lab</title>
            <link>https://auklab-audio.github.io/publications/2025/technological-evolution-at-auklab</link>
            <description>In 2008, we built an artificial nesting construction for Common Murres *Uria aalge*, the Karlsö Auk Lab, on an island in the Baltic Sea. The aim was to create an environment in which the birds could be readily monitored and technological equipment easily installed. Here we report on murre recruitment to the Auk Lab during its first decade, compare breeding performance with birds on natural cliff ledges, and revisit the original research questions. Dramatic developments in video surveillance, automated scales, thermal cameras, weather sensors and AI-driven analytics—unforeseen ten years ago—delivered data at an unprecedented temporal resolution. These technologies revealed major ecological insights, including the roles of eagle disturbance and heat stress, while highlighting challenges such as automated individual identification and the high costs of IT infrastructure. We outline new questions for the coming decade and invite further research collaborations. :contentReference[oaicite:2]{index=2}
  DOI: 10.5038/2074-1235.53.1.1612</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">10.5038/2074-1235.53.1.1612</guid>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>